Guide to the Lynne Tillman Papers 1939-2008 (Bulk 1984-2006) MSS.180
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series XX: Computer Disks, 192495
  - Series XX, Subseries B: Floppy Disks--Originals, 192496
    - "Twisted" Script 4.2, 5.1, scriptW42., word perfect 5.1, 192514 (Box 56, Disk ID: 180.3.0190)
    - Twisted 3/3/94 (current 5.1), 192513 (Box 56, Disk ID: 180.3.0191)
    - Love; letters 93/friends and lit; war and tour; Amy Fisher, 192512 (Box 56, Disk ID: 180.3.0192)
    - W.P. 4.2. Full. Script Laser #4, IIA cur has new changes, 192511 (Box 56, Disk ID: 180.3.0193)
    - Misc Twisted 8/24/94, 192510 (Box 56, Disk ID: 180.3.0194)
    - Let 91, Let 92, Lit 92; Elizabeth uncontrol body; Impossible man (w/imag) and (w/o images); Love Sentence 2/11/94; War/Tour (all), 192509 (Box 56, Disk ID: 180.3.0195)
    - Twistfin.LT; twv.tfin.LTA; 3/19 fonda letter; 3/21 :etter; 3/21 nuedits.cid;9:51 3/23 letter, 192508 (Box 56, Disk ID: 180.3.0196)
    - 8/13/96 script, 192507 (Box 56, Disk ID: 180.3.0197)
    - Acme Art, 212-941-6850; DOS6 Anti Virus Boot Disk; type A: 1 msav enter or reboot w/ disk in drive, 192506 (Box 56, Disk ID: 180.3.0198)
    - Ultraviolet, 192505 (Box 56, Disk ID: 180.3.0199)
    - 12/31/93 - Baldwin; Bottomly, 192504 (Box 56, Disk ID: 180.3.0200)
    - Fields; Mekas/Geldzah[k]Grossman; Name/ Maureen, 192503 (Box 56, Disk ID: 180.3.0201)
    - To: Lynne Tillman; CaleConv WP4.2, 192502 (Box 56, Disk ID: 180.3.0202)
    - Craig Antho, Watney C.O., Letters friends 91, Shore I, 192501 (Box 56, Disk ID: 180.3.0203)
    - Grossman, Geldzahler, Malanga, 192500 (Box 56, Disk ID: 180.3.0204)
    - J. Cala transcrip, Word Perfect; Stephen Shore (2+3), Mary Woronov, 192499 (Box 56, Disk ID: 180.3.0205)
    - Mead, Hartley, Shore IV, Morrissey, 192498 (Box 56, Disk ID: 180.3.0206)
    - Fastwire II disk (Untitled and no content), 192497 (Box 56, Disk ID: 180.3.0207)
- Series XXI: Objects, 192448
  - "Committed" T-shirt. Black velvety letters on white cotton., 192486 (Box 59, Object ID: 180.2.0009)
  - Lynne Tillman T-shirt. Photograph and signature on front, "The Avant-Gardes in New York Seiichi Tamaka" on reverse. White T-shirt. With original celophane/Tamaka sticker., 192485 (Box 59, Object ID: 180.2.0010)
  - "Absence Makes The Heart" T-shirt., 192484 (Box 59, Object ID: 180.2.0011)
  - "The Madame Realism Complex" T-shirt., 192483 (Box 59, Object ID: 180.2.0012)
  - Barbara Kruger, "Your body is a battleground. Support legal abortion, birth control, and Women's rights." T-shirt, 192482 (Box 60, Object ID: 180.2.0013)
  - Barbara Kruger, "When I hear the word Culture I take out my checkbook" t-shirt, 192481 (Box 60, Object ID: 180.2.0014)
  - Barbara Kruger, "I shop therefore I am", 192480 (Box 60, Object ID: 180.2.0015)
  - Barbara Kruger, "I can't look at you" T-shirt, 192479 (Box 60, Object ID: 180.2.0016)
  - "Certain Radio Speeches of Ezra Pound" T-shirt., 192478 (Box 60, Object ID: 180.2.0017)
  - John Zorn Cobra T-Shirt, 192477 (Box 61, Object ID: 180.2.0018)
  - Jazz trio T-Shirt, graphic by R. Lederman., 192476 (Box 61, Object ID: 180.2.0019)
  - "No Radio" Man with dog on bike T-shirt. J Humphrey graphic., 192475 (Box 61, Object ID: 180.2.0020)
  - Operation Minotaur T-shirt, 192474 (Box 61, Object ID: 180.2.0021)
  - "No More nice Girls" T-shirt., 192473 (Box 62, Object ID: 180.2.0022)
  - "Sorry to be LIVING!!!" T-shirt, 192472 (Box 62, Object ID: 180.2.0023)
  - "Caravaggio Film by Derek Jarman" T-shirt, 192471 (Box 62, Object ID: 180.2.0024)
  - "Don't be afraid" project T-shirt, 192470 (Box 63, Object ID: 180.2.0025)
  - "Don't give an inch" t-shirt, 192469 (Box 63, Object ID; 180.2.0026)
  - "Screws" T-shirt, 192468 (Box 63, Object ID: 180.2.0027)
  - Green headband with shamrock antena. Labeled, "Karen Finley World Tour 1990", 192467 (Box 63, Object ID: 180.2.0028)
  - Barbara Kruger "Don't be a jerk" bumper sticker., 192466 (Box 63, Object ID: 180.2.0029)
  - Barbara Kruger, "You are an experiment in terror" match books. 6 in celophane package., 192465 (Box 64, Object ID: 180.2.0030)
  - Barbara Kruger, "Charisma is the perfume of your gods" match books. 6 in celophane package., 192464 (Box 64, Object ID: 180.2.0031)
  - Barbara Kruger, "You construct intricate rituals which allow you to touch the skin of other men." 6 matchbooks in celephone package., 192463 (Box 64, Object ID: 180.2.0032)
  - Barbara Kruger, "Your manias become science" matchbooks. 6 in celophane package., 192462 (Box 64, Object ID: 180.2.0032)
  - "Cast in Doubt" rubber stamp., 192461 (Box 64, Object ID: 180.2.0033)
  - "Cast In Doubt/Lynne Tillman" rubber stamp, 192460 (Box 64, Object ID: 180.2.0034)
  - "Committed" rubber stamp, 192459 (Box 64, Object ID: 180.2.0035)
  - Plaster dental model, top and bottom., 192458 (Box 64, Object ID: 180.2.0036)
  - Plaster dental model of the right half of Lynne Tillman's mouth. Connected by a plastic hinge, 192457 (Box 64, Object ID: 180.2.0037)
  - Plaster dental model, top and bottom, 192456 (Box 64, Object ID: 180.2.0038)
  - Wrapped box tied with blue ribbon. Wax seals and pictures of urns decorate the outside. The inside is lined with blue satin and filled with tissue paper and confetti., 192455 (Box 64, Object ID: 180.2.0039)
  - Bell and Howell electric eye, super 8 camera., 192454; Broken plastic frame surrounding the rotating lenses. (Box 64, Object ID: 180.2.0040)
  - Framed photo collage by Tim Hailand. Inscribed "To Lynne Love - Tim (T. Hailand, 1991)", 192453 (Box 64, Object ID: 180.2.0041)
  - Drawing. Inscribed, "Deer Lin Merril love from Christopher", 192452 (Box 64, Object ID: 180.2.0042)
  - "I'll be the Judge. Women's Action Coalition" Black graphics on white cloth., 192451 (Box 64, Object ID: 180.2.0043)
  - "Postes" woven plastic bag., 192450 (Box 64, Object ID: 180.2.0044)
  - Three small pieces of fabric, 192449 (Box 64, Object ID: 180.2.0045)
- Oversize Series I: Correspondence, 192440
  Oversize Series I: Correspondence contains oversize materials from Series I.
  - Oversize I, Subseries A: Individuals and Institutions, 192443
    - Beard, Paul - card and sheet music, 1995-1996; 192447 (Box 70, Folder 1)
    - Blowdryer, Jennifer, 1991; 192446 (Box 70, Folder 2)
    - Grimson, Todd, 1993; 192445 (Box 70, Folder 3)
    - Stevenson, Harold, 2004; 192444 (Box 70, Folder 4)
  - Oversize I, Subseries D: Correspondence Files, 192441
    - Ford, Charles Henri, 1972-2003; 192442 (Box 70, Folder 5)
- Oversize Series II: Subject Files, 192406
  Oversize Series II: Subject Files contains oversize materials from Series II.
  - Oversize II, Subseries A: Artists, 192418
    - Albery, Nicholas - obituaries, 2001; 192439 (Box 70, Folder 6)
    - Angus, James, 1999; 192438 (Box 70, Folder 7)
    - Armstrong, David, 1993-1994; 192437 (Box 70, Folder 8)
    - Blake, Nayland, 1997-2003; 192436 (Box 70, Folder 9)
    - Blegvad, Peter - The Book of Leviathan, Undated; 192435 (Box 70, Folder 10)
    - Bowles, Jane and Paul - The Threepenny Review #21, 31, 1985-1987; 192434 (Box 70, Folder 11)
    - Bunn, David, Undated; 192433 (Box 70, Folder 12)
    - Cooper, Dennis, Undated; 192432 (Box 70, Folder 13)
    - Fish, Max - Drunk Driving Calendar, 1993; 192431 (Box 70, Folder 14)
    - Hawkins, Yolanda, Undated; 192430 (Box 70, Folder 15)
    - Hearn, Pat, 1995-2001; 192429 (Box 70, Folder 16)
      Removed from Box 10, Folder 43
    - Hofstra, Undated; 192428 (Box 70, Folder 17)
    - Hsieh, Tehching, 2000; 192427 (Box 70, Folder 18)
    - Kolbowski, Sylvia, Undated; 192426 (Box 70, Folder 19)
    - Minh-ha, Trinh - Critical Reflections in ArtForum, Undated; 192425 (Box 70, Folder 20)
    - Prina, Stephen, 1993; 192424 (Box 70, Folder 21)
    - Rosenberg, Aura, 2002; 192423 (Box 71, Folder 1)
    - Schumann, Christian, Undated; 192422 (Box 71, Folder 2)
    - Shore, Stephen, 2000; 192421 (Box 71, Folder 3)
    - Turyn, Anne, 1986; 192420 (Box 71, Folder 4)
    - Williams, Heathcote - Suck Solicitation, Undated; 192419 (Box 71, Folder 5)
  - Oversize II, Subseries B: Subjects, 192413
    - Collective for Living Cinema, Undated; 192417 (Box 71, Folder 6)
    - DSM Categories and Description - News articles about schizophrenia, MPD, etc..., 1975-1989; 192416 (Box 71, Folder 7)
      Removed from Box 13, Folder 8
    - Guerilla Girls Newsletter, 1994; 192415 (Box 71, Folder 8)
    - International - The Fanatic xeroxed Broadsheet Paper, 1986; 192414 (Box 71, Folder 9)
  - Oversize II, Subseries C: Photographic Material and Miscellaneous, 192407
    - Family Portrait of Unknown Family - photographer: Shirlet Clarke, Austin TX, Undated; 192412 (Box 71, Folder 10)
    - Fat City Cinema Club poster - Amsterdam, Undated; 192411 (Box 71, Folder 11)
    - Feet: The Inside Story - with card "To Val, From Dee and All", Undated; 192410 (Box 71, Folder 12)
    - Photograph of newspaper picture - girl, boy, and dog, Undated; 192409 (Box 71, Folder 13)
    - Van Hensen Century Shirt Advertisement featuring Ronald Reagan, Undated; 192408 (Box 71, Folder 14)
- Oversize Series IV: Committed (1984), 192399
  Oversize Series IV: Committed contains oversize materials from Series IV.
  - Oversize IV, Subseries A: Drafts and Production, 192404
    - Frances Farmer Paperdoll - Zuilen, D., 1982; 192405 (Box 71, Folder 15)
  - Oversize IV, Subseries B: Publicity and Distribution, 192400
    - Committed - Black and White photograph, Undated; 192403 (Box 71, Folder 19)
    - Princeton - Women and Film Series, including Committed, 1995; 192402 (Box 71, Folder 18)
    - Village Voice - "The Price of Admission...", "Frances Farmer's Dark Victory...", 1982; 192401 (Box 71, Folder 17)
- Oversize Series V: Haunted Houses (1987), 192396
  Oversize Series V: Haunted Houses contains oversize materials from Series V.
  - Oversize V, Subseries B: Publicity and Distribution, 192397
    - London - Promotional Poster for Haunted Houses, Undated; 192398 (Box 71, Folder 16)
- Oversize Series VII: Cast in Doubt (1992), 192390
  Oversize Series VII: Cast in Doubt contains oversize materials from Series VII.
  - Oversize VII, Subseries A: Drafts and Production, 192393
    - Cast in Doubt cover, Undated; 192395 (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - Cast in Doubt cover - color copy, Undated; 192394 (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Oversize VII, Subseries B: Publicity and Distribution, 192391
    - Voice Literary Supplement - Reviews in Lit Hit, 1992; 192392 (Box 42, Folder 2)
- Oversize Series VIII: The Velvet Years (1995), 192383
  Oversize Series VIII: The Velvet Years contains oversize materials from Series VIII.
  - Oversize VIII, Subseries A: Drafts and Production, 192384
    - The Velvet Years - Color copy of cover, Undated; 192389 (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Galleys - before fifty images attached, Undated; 192388 (Box 41, Folder 11)
    - Paperback cover, Undated; 192387 (Box 41, Folder 10)
    - Photocopies of redesign, Undated; 192386 (Box 41, Folder 9)
    - Warhol File, Undated; 192385 (Box 45, Folder 19)
- Oversize Series IX: No Lease on Life (1997), 192380
  Oversize Series IX: No Lease on Life contains oversize materials from Series IX.
  - Oversize IX, Subseries A: Drafts and Production, 192381
    - Covers and Jackets, Undated; 192382 (Box 45, Folder 20)
- Oversize Series X: Bookstore (1999), 192377
  Oversize Series X: Bookstore contains oversize materials from Series X.
  - Oversize X, Subseries A: Drafts and Production, 192378
    - Photo proofs, 1999; 192379 (Box 41, Folder 8)
- Oversize Series XII: Essay and Story Collections, 192374
  Oversize Series XII: Essay and Story Collections contains oversize materials from Series XII.
  - Oversize XII, Subseries D: This is Not It (2002), 192375
    - Juan Munoz - "This is Not It" for Parkett photos, Undated; 192376 (Box 41, Folder 7)
- Oversize Series XIII: Other Works and Activities, 192345
  Oversize Series XIII: Other Works and Activities contains oversize materials from Series XIII.
  - Oversize XIII, Subseries A: Writing, Readings, and Artwork, 192358
    - Bomb - Lynne Tillman's "Cast in Doubt", 1992; 192373 (Box 69, Folder 2)
    - Bomb #57 - "Peter Dreher" by Lynne Tillman; #59 - "Kendall Thomas" by Lynne Tillman, 1996-1997; 192372 (Box 69, Folder 3)
    - Cinderella - Sketches, Undated; 192371 (Box 69, Folder 5)
    - Ideolects #9 and #10 - Cover mockup, Undated; 192370 (Box 69, Folder 6)
    - Lynne Tillman Reads in Brighton - poster, Undated; 192369 (Box 69, Folder 7)
    - Lynne Tillman - Wexner prize for Yvonne Rainer, 1995; 192368 (Box 69, Folder 9)
    - Paranoid's Annonymous Newsletter #1,2,3, 1976-1979; 192367 (Box 69, Folder 1)
    - "Pleasure isn't a Pretty Picture" - Large black and white photograph, Aura Rosenberg, Undated; 192366 (Box 69, Folder 8)
      Removed from Box 29, Folder 5
    - Published Pieces: Artpaper, 1990; 192365 (Box 69, Folder 4)
    - Published Pieces - Bomb, 1987; 192364 (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Published Pieces - A Vtre Extra, Fluxus, 1979; 192363 (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - Slant: Lynne Tillman on the Autobiography of Eve - Art Forum originals, April 1990; 192362 (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - Stockholder - Sketches, Undated; 192361 (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - Voice Literary Supplement #105 - "A Dark Background" by Lynne Tillman, 1992; 192360 (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - Word - "The Last Word", Lynne Tillman on "Exposures", 1995; 192359 (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Oversize XIII, Subseries B: Editing, 192352
    - Americans Abroad, Undated; 192357 (Box 43, Folder 16)
    - Americans Abroad - Mockup, Undated; 192356 (Box 42)
    - Craig Owens Project - Article masters, 1978; 192355 (Box 43, Folder 17)
      Removed from Box 31, Folder 34
    - Exhibition poster for Roni Horn, Undated; 192354 (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - Guerilla Text galleys, 1996; 192353 (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Oversize XIII, Subseries C: Publicity, 192348
    - Haunted Houses and Committed - event poster, Undated; 192351 (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - Patrick McGrath interviews Lynne Tillman for Bomb Magazine, 1991; 192350 (Box 43, Folder 3)
      Removed from Box 32, Folder 63
    - Stroemfeld/Roterstern Bag - Including Lynne Tillman's name, Undated; 192349 (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Oversize XIII, Subseries D: Notes and Fragments, 192346
    - Dutch Film Maker's Coop amd Discussion of Films - including Lynne Tillman, Undated; 192347 (Box 43, Folder 1)
- Oversize Series XIV: Education, 192341
  Oversize Series XIV: Education contains oversize materials from Series XIV.
  - Oversize XIV, Subseries A: Secondary and Undergraduate, 192342
    - Brighton Writer's Conference poster, Undated; 192344 (Box 43, Folder 8)
    - Feminism / Film / Looking - Readings, Undated; 192343 (Box 43, Folder 7)
- Oversize Series XV: Printed Material, 192327
  Oversize Series XV: Printed Material contains oversize materials from Series XV.
  - Autonomedia Calendar, 1993; 192340 (Box 43, Folder 12)
  - Fandadangos, 1975; 192339 (Box 43, Folder 10)
  - het Gewicht #3, 1977; 192338 (Box 43, Folder 11)
  - Illuminatus!, 1977; 192337 (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - Interview magazine - Andy Mania, 1996; 192336 (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Life 55:22 - JFK Assasination, 1963; 192335 (Box 43, Folder 13)
  - Life 55:23 - JFK Funeral, 1963; 192334 (Box 43, Folder 14)
  - See Magazine, 1948; 192333 (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - Straat #3, 1977; 192332 (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - Suck #1,2,3,7 - #1 used for Franklin Furnace exhibit, Undated; 192331 (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Suck: Special Issue - The Virgin Sperm Dancer - Franklin Furnace Bookworks exhibition, 1972; 192330 (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - a VTRE Extra #11, 1979; 192329 (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Witch Craft in the Jordan, Undated; 192328 (Box 44, Folder 5)
- Oversize Series XVI: Posters, 192286
  Scope and Content n
  Oversize Series XVI: Posters contains posters for conferences, film festivals, art shows, readings, etc.
  - AC/DC by Heathcote Williams, Undated; 192326 (Flat-file-folder 31)
  - Art Projekt '92, 1992; 192325 (Box 45, Folder 12)
  - Blueprint drawings for Lynne Tillman's Study, by Molly Hankowitz, Undated; 192324 (Flat-file-folder 29)
  - Bogosian - Sex, Drugs, Rock and Roll, Undated; 192323 (Box 45, Folder 18)
  - Charles Henri Ford - Printed Matter 1929-1969, 1999; 192322 (Box 45, Folder 17)
  - Christian Boltanski - "Lost: New York Projects", Undated; 192321 (Box 45, Folder 16)
  - Committed - Outstanding Film of the Year Award, London Film Festival, 1984; 192320 (Box 45, Folder 15)
  - Communism and the U.S.: History and Consequences, 1988; 192319 (Box 45, Folder 14)
    Removed from Series XIIIA, Box 25, Folder 25
  - Conference on Youth Music, Youth Culture, Undated; 192318 (Box 45, Folder 13)
  - Conference Posters - NYU "A to the K: New Directions in Popular Music", "La Guerre Indirect, En Direct", Princeton - "Sexuality and Space", 192317 (Folder 12 Left)
  - Crime Calendar, Undated; 192316 (Flat-file-folder 32)
  - Critical Fiction - Dia Art Foundation, Undated; 192315 (Folder 13 Left)
  - Daniella Rossell - "Third World Blondes Have More Fun", 2002; 192314 (Box 45, Folder 11)
  - David Salle, 1982; 192313 (Flat-file-folder 33)
  - Event Posters and Container Notes, Undated; 192312 (Folder 14 Left)
  - Exotic Events - Times Square Show, Undated; 192311 (Folder 16 Right)
  - "The Fatted Calf" by Jeremy Sanford, Undated; 192310 (Box 45, Folder 10)
  - Franklin Furnace Fights for First Amendment Rights, 1990; 192309 (Folder 17 Right)
  - Gregory Crewdson at Luhring Augustine, 2002; 192308 (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Hallwalls - "Picture This: Films Chosen by Artists" including Specter of the Rose by Lynne Tillman, 1981; 192307 (Folder 18 Right)
  - Haunted Houses - Poster from Barnes and Noble and container note, Undated; 192306 (Folder 15 Right)
  - Ink Painting, Undated; 192305 (Folder 12 Left)
  - Intercat '76 - The Bicentennial Cat Film Festival, 1976; 192304 (Box 43, Folder 15)
  - Jack Pierson, 1998; 192303 (Folder 19 Right)
  - Jane Arden's "Vagina Rex and the Gas Oven", Undated; 192302 (Folder 20 Right)
  - Last Dance - Photographic Exhibition, 1986; 192301 (Folder 21 Right)
  - Leven en Werk von Jane Bowles, Undated; 192300 (Folder 11 Left)
  - Negotiations in the Contact Zone, 192299 (Folder 22 Right)
    Removed from Series XIII, Box 25, Folder 29
  - Palladium Exhibition, 1985; 192298 (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Peter Cain at Matther Marks Gallery, 1997; 192297 (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Poetry Project's Annual New Years Day Readings, including Lynne Tillman, 1996-2000; 192296 (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Posters from book boxes, 1995; 192295 (Folder 23 Right)
  - Princeton Architecture Lecture Series, 1995-1996; 192294 (Flat-file-folder 30)
  - Reactions - Exit Art, Undated; 192293 (Folder 24 Right)
  - Re-Positions film program including "Committed", Undated; 192292 (Box 45, Folder 2)
    Removed from Series IV B, Box 15, Folder 6
  - Sam Taylor-Wood - The Passion; Third Party, 2000-2002; 192291 (Folder 25 Right)
  - "She Must Be Seeing Things" - a film by Sheila McLaughlin, Undated; 192290 (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - Viewpoints - A Conference on Women, Culture, and Public Media, 1986; 192289 (Box 45, Folder 9)
    Removed from Series XIII A, Box 30, Folder 30
  - Williams, Heathcote - Elephants newspaper, Undated; 192288 (Box 45, Folder 8)
  - Yasujiro Ozu - Anthology Film Archive, Undated; 192287 (Box 45, Folder 7)